# SAMARPAN RAI

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

A creative developer with three years' experience in the IT industry. Experiences ranging from, embedded developer for a company in Nepal, API Developer for a startup company in Paris.

I am currently working as Product Manager for startup company based in Nijmegen (Netherlands) but also looking for the right opportunity to use my technical expertise and explore the Big Data horizon.



# PERSONAL INFORMATION

DOB: 1st August 1994

Place of birth: Siliguri, India

Nationality: Indian

Work phone: +31 625 297 625

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/samarpan-rai

Contact Email : <a href="mailto:samarpantrai@gmail.com">samarpantrai@gmail.com</a>

### **E**XPERIENCE

Product Manager: EyeSense, Feb 2018- Present

Aiding with marketing, system design, feedback collection and data insight reporting

WAITER: Sumo, Dec 2017- Present

Waiter at Sumo restaurant in Nijmegen.

**SOCIAL MEDIA AMBASSADOR**: Radboud University, Mar 2017- Aug 2017 Creating Bachelor's of Artificial Intelligence <u>facebook</u> and <u>instagram</u> from scratch. Responsible for uploading content and interacting with students.

**Marketting and Adminstrator**: Radboud University, June 2017 – July 2017

Calling prospective students from India, corresponding with email and helping the students if they have any confusions.

**WEB INTEGRATION DEVELOPER**: WYND (Paris, France), Nov 2015 – May 2016

Investigating, proposing and providing solutions for cheaper communication between remote autonomous payment devices.

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**: KAZI STUDIOS (Kathmandu, Nepal), Apr 2014 – Oct 2015

Extensive work on PHP and integrating with the new paradigm of MVC in practice. Also worked on some challenging CMS like Magento and Mediawiki. I still worked on Hardware project. One of them is called Sajha, which would track the public vehicles of Kathmandu. We are the first one to bring this management in the country.

#### **EDUCATION**

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**: Artificial Intelligence, Radboud University, 2016 – Present

**BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE**: American University of Paris (Paris, France), 2015 – 2016

**INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE DIPLOMA PROGRAMME :** Ullens School (Kathmandu, Nepal), 2012 – 2014

## SKILL SET Coding

Web developement experience with backend specilization using PHP derviate platforms like Symfony.

Data mining experience with background in modelling and data visualisation using python libraries like sk-learn, pandas and numpy for quick prototype.

Moderate data analysis experience with R

## **Design**

Create simple but working pages for sites using HTML/CSS/Javascript. Some knowledge of photoshop and blender.

### **Hardware**

Arduino enthusiast for personal and Raspberry for work project for Smart Home automation.

### **LANGUAGE**

**English** - Full professional proficiency

Nepali - Mother tongue

**Hindi** - Professional working proficiency

French - Limited working proficiency

**Dutch** - Elementary proficiency